Guide to the James J. Hill Addresses 1902-1916
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
James J. Hill Addresses
1902-1916
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Cage 295
Hill, James Jerome, 1838-1916
.5 linear feet of shelf space 1 box
Addresses by James J. Hill, delivered to various groups on transportation, commercial affairs, and education.
James Jerome Hill (1838-1916) was a famous Canadian-born American industrialist, best known for his achievements as the head of the Great Northern Railway Company.
This collection consists of published addresses of American railroad executive James J. Hill (pamphlets).
This collection is arranged in a single series in chronological order.
This collection is open and available for research use.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Railroads; Speeches, addresses, etc.
Railroads
- Address of James J. Hill to the Illinois Manufacturer's Association, Chicago, Illinois, 1904 June 4 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Paper prepared by Mr. James J. Hill on Irrigation, read at National Irrigation Conference, Portland, Oregon, 1905 August 21 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- The Nation's future: address delivered by Mr. James J. Hill at the Minnesota State Fair, St. Paul, Minnesota, 1906 September 3 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Development of the Northwest: address delivered before the Chicago Commercial Association, 1906 October 6 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Chicago's interest in reciprocity with Canada: address before the Merchants' Club of Chicago, 1906 November 10 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- The transportation problem of the United States: letter of Mr. James J. Hill to Hon. John A. Johnson, Governor of Minnesota, 1907 January 14 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Address delivered by Mr. James J. Hill before the Kansas City, Missouri Commercial Club, 1907 November 19 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Address delivered by Mr. James J. Hill before the National Rivers and Harbors Congress, Washington, D.C., 1907 December 5 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- The natural wealth of the land and its conservation: Address delivered by Mr. James J. Hill at the Conference on the Conservation of National Resources, Washington, D.C., 1908 May 13-15 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Address delivered at the Memorial Day exercises, St. Paul, Minnesota, 1908 May 30 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Address by Mr. James J. Hill, at the dedication of Stephens Hall, Crookston, Minnesota, 1908 September 17 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- The future of rail and water transportation: letter of James J. Hill, read at the Lakes-to-the-Gulf Deep Waterway Association Convention, Chicago, Illinois, 1908 October 7-9 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Address delivered by Mr. James J. Hill at the annual banquet of the Chamber of Commerce of the State of New York, Waldorf-Astoria, New York, 1908 November 19 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Address delivered by Mr. James J. Hill before the Farmers' National Congress, Madison, Wisconsin, 1908 September 24 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Address delivered by Mr. James J. Hill at the twentieth annual commencement exercises of the School of Agriculture of the University of Minnesota, 1909 March 24 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Address of Mr. James J. Hill, read at the ceremonies for unveiling a statue of the late William Colvill, colonel of the First Regiment of Minnesota Volunteers, in the State Capitol at St. Paul, Minnesota, 1909 March 31 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Address delivered by Mr. James J. Hill at the opening of the Alaska-Yukon-Pacific Exposition, Seattle, Washington, 1909 June 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- National wealth and the farm. Address delivered by Mr. James J. Hill at the thirty-fifth annual Convention of the American Bankers Association, 1909 September 14 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Speech of J.J. Hill on President Taft's day at the Montana State Fair at Helena, 1909 September 27 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Address delivered by Mr. James J. Hill at the National Corn Exposition, Omaha, Nebraska, 1909 December 9 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- The conservation of capital: address of James J. Hill at the Minnesota Conservation and Agricultural Development Congress, Saint Paul, Minnesota, 1910 March 17 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Address delivered by Mr. James J. Hill before the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen, St. Paul Auditorium, 1910 June 17 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Traffic growth and terminal needs. Read at the Convention of the Millers' National Federation, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1910 June 22-24 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Address delivered by Mr. James J. Hill at the National Conservation Congress, St. Paul, Minnesota, 1910 September 5-9 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Paper by James J. Hill read at the Portland Fair and Live Stock Exposition, Portland, Oregon, 1910 September 5-11 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Address delivered by Mr. James J. Hill before the Chicago Association of Commerce, Chicago, Illinois, 1911 February 15 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Address delivered by Mr. James J. Hill before the Illinois Bankers Association, Springfield, Illinois, 1911 October 11 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- What is the Northwest Development League?, circa 1912 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- The Great Northern and the Northwest: James J. Hill's letter to the stockholders on retiring from the chairmanship of the board of directors, 1912 July 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Minnesota's agriculture: address delivered by Mr. James J. Hill at the second Minnesota Conservation and Agricultural Development Congress, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1912 November 19 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- The country's need of greater railway facilities and terminals: address at the annual dinner of the Railway Business Association, New York City, 1912 December 19 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- The use and abuse of credit: address delivered by Mr. James J. Hill before the St. Paul Association of Credit Men at their annual banquet at the St. Paul Hotel, 1913 February 11 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Industry credit and banking: address delivered at the convention of the American Bankers Association, Boston, Massachusetts, 1913 October 9 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Investment bonds: an address by James J. Hill delivered at the Convention of Investment Bankers Association of America, Chicago, 1913 October 30 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- The future of foreign trade: paper read at the National Foreign Trade Convention, Washington, D.C., 1914 May 27-28 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Credit and railways after the war: paper read at a meeting of The Business Men's League of St. Louis, 1914 October 7 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- The outlook for business: Address by Mr. James J. Hill at the annual dinner of the Chamber of Commerce of Rochester, N.Y., 1914 December 5 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Freedom for our foreign trade: read at Second National Foreign Trade Convention, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 January 21-22 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- How to help business: read at the annual dinner of the Traffic Club of Chicago, Illinois, 1915 February 25 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- The publisher and his public: read at the twenty-ninth annual dinner of the American Newspaper Publishers Association, New York City, 1915 April 22 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Preparedness for peace, circa 1916 (Box 1, Folder 8)